Guide to the Morris Edward Opler papers, [ca. 1960-1996]
Opler, Morris Edward papers, [ca. 1960-1996]
- Series VI: India
  - Subseries A: Gohana Kala
    - M.E.O. slides (captions) (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Senapur Study notes, October, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Senapur Study notes, November, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Senapur Study notes, December, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Senapur Study notes, Jan., 1948 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Senapur Study notes, Feb., 1948 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Senapur Study notes, March, 1948 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Senapur Study notes, April, 1948 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Senapur Study notes, May, 1948 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Senapur Study notes, Feb., 1947 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Senapur Study notes, March, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Senapur Study notes, April, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Senapur Study notes, May, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - Senapur Study notes, June, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Senapur Study notes, July, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence and photographs (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Hoffman, Joseph Killer of Enemies (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - India, bibliographies, general (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - India, bibliographies, specific topics (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Opler, M.E., Bibliography (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Opler, M.E., Issues Arising from the Evacuation and Detention of Nisei and Issei During World War II (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - Opler, M.E., Special Bibliographies (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - The Case for the Nisei Reprinted by JACL (Box 116, Folder 8)
    - Hirabayashi case (Box 116, Folder 9)
    - Pamphlets and photographs of St. Joseph's Mission, Mescalero, NM (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - The First Ancestors of Hui Muslims (Box 116, Folder 11)
    - Opler, M.E., Anthropological Theory Bibliography (Box 116, Folder 12, 13)
    - Address Book (Box 116, Folder 14)
    - US Supreme Court: Korematsu Case, Evacuation, US Ninth Circuit of Appeals Court Brief, Citizenship (Box 116, Folder 15)
  - Subseries B: Senapur Enlargement File
    - Extra (smaller, mounted) Rankhandi Photos (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Rankhandi Photo Prints (Material Culture) (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Rankhandi Photo Prints (Material Culture) (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Jhabiran Photos (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Senapur File Categories (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Senapur Photos (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Senapur Photo Categories (Dividers only) (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Senapur Proverbs and Sayings (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Senapur Photos Key (BC 101-500) (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Senapur Photos (BC 401a-523a) JP, SP, WH, TY, ANON, PA, WR 1-100 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Senapur Photos (WR 101-700) (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Senapur Photos (WR 701-1162), Mo Photos (1949-50): A2-A85 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Mo Photos (1949-50): A86-D64 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Mo Photos (1949-50): D68-F93b (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Senapur Enlargement File
      - Action Research, Misc.: Community Hand Pump (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - Action Research, Misc.: Government Program (Box 76, Folder 4)
      - Action Research, Misc.: Shramdan (Box 76, Folder 5)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Project Personnel (Box 76, Folder 6)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Project Worker with Informant (Box 76, Folder 7)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Project House (Box 76, Folder 8)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Project House (Baranpur) (Box 76, Folder 9)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Furniture for Project House (Box 76, Folder 10)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Hand Pump Installed by Project (Box 76, Folder 11)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Potato Contest (Box 76, Folder 12)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Improved Plow (Box 76, Folder 13)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Furniture and Generator Donated to School by Project (Box 76, Folder 14)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Generator Donated to School by Project (Box 76, Folder 15)
      - Action Research, Cornell U. Project: Science Equipment Donated to School by Project (Box 76, Folder 16)
      - Animals, Misc.: Domestic Animals (Box 76, Folder 17)
      - Animals, Misc.: Snakes (Box 76, Folder 18)
      - Animals, Animal Husbandry: Feeding Cattle (Box 76, Folder 19)
      - Animals, Animal Husbandry: Inoculating Cattle (Box 76, Folder 20)
      - Caste, Misc.: Chamar Caste Panchayat (Box 76, Folder 21)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Ahir (Box 76, Folder 22)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Barai (Box 76, Folder 23)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Bhat (Box 76, Folder 24)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Bin (Box 76, Folder 25)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Chamar (Box 76, Folder 26)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Dafali (Box 76, Folder 27)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Darzi (Box 76, Folder 28)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Dasunhi (Box 76, Folder 29)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Dharikar (Box 76, Folder 30)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Dhobi (Box 76, Folder 31)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Garariya (Box 76, Folder 32)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Hela (Box 76, Folder 33)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Kahar (Box 76, Folder 34)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Kalvar (Box 76, Folder 35)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Kohar (Box 76, Folder 36)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Lohar (Box 76, Folder 37)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Mochi (Box 76, Folder 38)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Musahar (Box 76, Folder 39)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Nai (Box 76, Folder 40)
      - Caste, Caste Work: Noniya (Box 76, Folder 41)
      - Change, Land Consolidation: Old Land Map (Box 76, Folder 42)
      - Change, Land Consolidation: New Land Map (Box 76, Folder 43)
      - Change, Land Consolidation: Court (Box 76, Folder 44)
      - Change, Land Consolidation: Ceremonial Activies (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - Change, Land Consolidation: Marked Fields (Box 77, Folder 2)
      - Change, Land Consolidation: Old Agricultural Methods in Consolidation Area (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Change, Kuti: Mill Complex (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Change, Kuti: Sugar Mill (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - Conflict and Crime, Miscellaneous (Box 77)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Miscellaneous: Basket Making (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Miscellaneous: Basket Weaving (Box 77, Folder 7)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Miscellaneous: Cleaning Kitchen Utensils (Box 77, Folder 8)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Miscellaneous: Daily Activities (Box 77, Folder 9)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Miscellaneous: Domestic Tasks (Box 77, Folder 10)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Miscellaneous: Parda Behavior (Box 77, Folder 11)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Fuel Preparation: Making Dung Cakes (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Fuel Preparation: Drying Dung Cakes (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Fuel Preparation: Stacking Dung Cakes (Box 77, Folder 14)
      - Custom and Etiquette, House Care: Applying Cow Dung Paste to Floor (Box 77, Folder 15)
      - Custom and Etiquette, House Care: Plastering Wall (Box 77, Folder 16)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Personal Care: Daily Activities- Bathing (Box 77, Folder 17)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Personal Care: Daily Activities- Tooth Care (Box 77, Folder 18)
      - Custom and Etiquette, Personal Care: Daily Activities- Washing Clothes (Box 77, Folder 19)
      - Dress and Ornaments, Miscellaneous: Thakur (Box 77, Folder 20)
      - Dress and Ornaments, Miscellaneous: Jewelry (Box 77, Folder 21)
      - Dress and Ornaments, Miscellaneous: Chamar Bracelets (Box 77, Folder 22)
      - Dress and Ornaments, Miscellaneous: Shoes (Box 77, Folder 23)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Miscellaneous- Cutting Grass (Box 77, Folder 24)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Miscellaneous- Carrying Grass (Box 77, Folder 25)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Miscellaneous- Cutting Fodder (Box 77, Folder 26)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Preparation of Fields- Digging with Mattock (Kudar) (Box 77, Folder 27)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Preparation of Fields- Plowing (Box 77, Folder 28)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Preparation of Fields- Leveling (Box 77, Folder 29)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Preparation of Fields- Fertilizing (Box 77, Folder 30)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Seed Selection and Sowing- Seed Selection (Box 77, Folder 31)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Seed Selection and Sowing- Obtaining Seed (Box 77, Folder 32)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Seed Selection and Sowing- Sowing (Box 77, Folder 33)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Irrigation- Irrigation (Box 77, Folder 34)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Irrigation- Basket Irrigation (Box 77, Folder 35)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Irrigation- by long, scoop-like implement (Don) (Box 77, Folder 36)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Irrigation- by wooden scoop (Hatta) (Box 77, Folder 37)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Irrigation- Well Irrigation (Box 77, Folder 38)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Growing Crops and Crop Cutting- Growing Crops (Box 77, Folder 39)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Growing Crops and Crop Cutting- Guarding Growing Crops (Box 77, Folder 40)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Growing Crops and Crop Cutting- Crop Cutting (Box 77, Folder 41)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Growing Crops and Crop Cutting- Crop Cutting and Burning (Box 77, Folder 42)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Harvesting, Threshing, and Winnowing- Harvesting (Box 77, Folder 43)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Harvesting, Threshing, and Winnowing- Threshing (Box 77, Folder 44)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Harvesting, Threshing, and Winnowing- Threshing by Bullocks (Box 77, Folder 45)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Harvesting, Threshing, and Winnowing- Threshing by Hand (Box 77, Folder 46)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Harvesting, Threshing, and Winnowing- Winnowing (Box 77, Folder 47)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Barley Cultivation (Box 77, Folder 48)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Corn Cultivation- Good Corn Crop (Box 77, Folder 49)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Corn Cultivation- Poor Corn Crop (Box 77, Folder 50)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Millet Cultivation (Box 77, Folder 51)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Potato Cultivation (Box 77, Folder 52)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Rice Cultivation- Plowing Rice Fields (Box 77, Folder 53)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Rice Cultivation- Sowing Rice Seed (Box 77, Folder 54)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Rice Cultivation- Transplanting Rice (Box 77, Folder 55)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Rice Cultivation- Harvesting Rice (Box 77, Folder 56)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Rice Cultivation- Threshing Rice (Box 77, Folder 57)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Soaking Sugar Cane Stalks (Box 77, Folder 58)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Sowing Sugar Cane (Box 77, Folder 59)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Hoeing Sugar Cane (Box 77, Folder 60)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Irrigating Sugar Cane Fields (Box 77, Folder 61)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Good and Poor Sugar Cane Crops (Box 77, Folder 62)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Harvesting Sugar Cane (Box 77, Folder 63)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Crushing Sugar Cane (Box 77, Folder 64)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Straining Sugar Cane Juice (Box 77, Folder 65)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Boiling Sugar Cane Juice (Box 77, Folder 66)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Manufacturing Brown Sugar (Gur) (Box 77, Folder 67)
      - Economy, Agriculture: Sugar Cane Cultivation- Brown Sugar (Gur) (Box 77, Folder 68)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Miscellaneous- Economy, Payment in Kind (Box 77, Folder 69)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Miscellaneous- Land Records Officers (Patvaris) (Box 77, Folder 70)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Miscellaneous- Tax Collecting (Box 77, Folder 71)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Industrial Activities (Non-Caste)- Basket Making (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Industrial Activities (Non-Caste)- Fishing (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Industrial Activities (Non-Caste)- Making Brass Tacks (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Industrial Activities (Non-Caste)- Making Spice Grinder (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Industrial Activities (Non-Caste)- Making Sweets (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Industrial Activities (Non-Caste)- Metal Working (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Industrial Activities (Non-Caste)- Rope Making (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Industrial Activities (Non-Caste)- Sewing (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Industrial Activities (Non-Caste)- Spinning (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Marketing- Economy (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Marketing- General Store (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Marketing- Brown Sugar (Gur) (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Marketing- Selling Fish (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - Economy, Non-Agricultural Activities: Marketing- Transporting Goods (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Education, Miscellaneous: Meeting Re Senapur Jr. HS (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Education, Miscellaneous: Partly Constructed School Building (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - Education, Miscellaneous: Education Week (Box 78, Folder 8)
      - Education, Miscellaneous: Laying the Foundation of Kanaura School (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - Education, Teaching and Studying: Classes in Session (Box 78, Folder 10)
      - Education, Teaching and Studying: Senapur Primary School Children (Box 78, Folder 11)
      - Education, Teaching and Studying: Senapur Students (Box 78, Folder 12)
      - Education, Teaching and Studying: Studying (Box 78, Folder 13)
      - Entertainment and Recreation, Miscellaneous: Games- Cowries (Kauri) (Box 78, Folder 14)
      - Entertainment and Recreation, Miscellaneous: Recreation (Box 78, Folder 15)
      - Entertainment and Recreation, Miscellaneous: Playing Cards (Box 78, Folder 16)
      - Entertainment and Recreation, Miscellaneous: Swimming in Ponds (Box 78, Folder 17)
      - Entertainment and Recreation, Miscellaneous: Wrestling (Kushati) (Box 78, Folder 18)
      - Entertainment and Recreation, School Tournaments: Gymnastic Tournament- Kanura (Box 78, Folder 19)
      - Entertainment and Recreation, School Tournaments: School Tournament (Box 78, Folder 20)
      - Entertainment and Recreation, School Tournaments: School (Circle) Tournament (Box 78, Folder 21)
      - Food, Miscellaneous: Milking Buffalo (Box 78, Folder 22)
      - Food, Food Preparation: Cleaning Grain (Box 78, Folder 23)
      - Food, Food Preparation (Box 78, Folder 24)
      - Food, Food Preparation: Grinding Grain (Box 78, Folder 25)
      - Food, Food Preparation: Grinding Spices (Box 78, Folder 26)
      - Food, Food Preparation: Pounding Grain (Box 78, Folder 27)
      - Food, Food Preparation: Pounding Rice (Box 78, Folder 28)
      - Health, Miscellaneous (Box 78, Folder 29)
      - House, Miscellaneous: House Types (Box 78, Folder 30)
      - House, Miscellaneous: Inner Courtyards (Box 78, Folder 31)
      - House, Miscellaneous: Man's Apartment (Dalan) (Box 78, Folder 31)
      - House, Building Construction: Building Construction (Box 78, Folder 33)
      - House, Building Construction: Digging Mud for Walls (Box 78, Folder 34)
      - House, Building Construction: Leaf Roof (Box 78, Folder 35)
      - House, Building Construction: Tile Making (Box 78, Folder 36)
      - House, Building Construction: Senapur Jr. High School (Box 78, Folder 37)
      - House, Building Construction: Baranpur School (Box 78, Folder 38)
      - Life Cycle, Birth (6th and 12th Day Ceremonies): Sixth Day Ceremony (Box 78, Folder 39)
      - Life Cycle, Birth (6th and 12th Day Ceremonies): Women Singing Sohar (Box 78, Folder 40)
      - Life Cycle, Birth (6th and 12th Day Ceremonies): Mul Shanti (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Life Cycle, Childhood and Adolescence: Miscellaneous- Child Behavior (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - Life Cycle, Childhood and Adolescence: Miscellaneous- Child Care and Bathing (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - Life Cycle, Childhood and Adolescence: Miscellaneous- Children Playing (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Life Cycle, Childhood and Adolescence: Pictures of Children (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Life Cycle, Childhood and Adolescence: Pictures of Children- Chamar (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Life Cycle, Childhood and Adolescence: Pictures of Children- Dharikar (Box 79, Folder 7)
      - Life Cycle, Childhood and Adolescence: Pictures of Children- Kahar (Box 79, Folder 8)
      - Life Cycle, Childhood and Adolescence: Pictures of Children- Noniya (Box 79, Folder 9)
      - Life Cycle, Childhood and Adolescence: Pictures of Children- Teli (Box 79, Folder 10)
      - Life Cycle, Childhood and Adolescence: Pictures of Children- Thakur (Box 79, Folder 11)
      - Life Cycle, Death: Death Rites (Box 79, Folder 12)
      - Life Cycle, Death: Death Rites- Chulha Nikalna (Box 79, Folder 13)
      - Life Cycle, Hair Cutting Ceremony (Box 79, Folder 14)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Thakur Tilak Ceremony (Box 79, Folder 15)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Urda Chuna (Box 79, Folder 16)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Haldi Matmangara (Box 79, Folder 17)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Parchan Ceremony (Box 79, Folder 18)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Departure of Groom for Bride's Village (Box 79, Folder 19)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: House Decorations (Box 79, Folder 20)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Food Preparation (Box 79, Folder 21)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Band (Box 79, Folder 22)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Band and Entertainers (Box 79, Folder 23)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Thakur (Box 79, Folder 24)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Thakur Tilak Wedding Jewelry (Box 79, Folder 25)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage (Box 79, Folder 26)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Bandanvar (Box 79, Folder 27)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Gauna (I) (Box 79, Folder 28)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Gauna (Marikpur) (II) (Box 79, Folder 29)
      - Life Cycle, Marriage: Gauna (III) (Box 79, Folder 30)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Bicycle (Box 79, Folder 31)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Bullock Cart (Box 79, Folder 32)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Cattle Troughs (Box 79, Folder 33)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Digging Tool (Pharasa) (Box 79, Folder 34)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Grain Baskets (Box 79, Folder 35)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Grain-Grinding Mill (Box 79, Folder 36)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Grinding Stones for Spices (Box 79, Folder 37)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Hand Mill (Box 79, Folder 38)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Harmonium (Box 79, Folder 39)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Household Utensils (Box 79, Folder 40)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Kitchen Utensils (Box 79, Folder 41)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Lamps (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Mechanical Chaff Cutter (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Medicine Dispenser for Animals (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Metal Buckets (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Metal Container often used for water (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Metal Trunk (Box 80, Folder 6)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Net for Picking Mangoes (Box 80, Folder 7)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Plow(s) incl. Improved Plow (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Pottery Kiln (Box 80, Folder 9)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Rice Pounder (Box 80, Folder 10)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Spear(Bala) (Box 80, Folder 11)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Stool (Box 80, Folder 12)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Stool and Metal Containers for a Meal (Box 80, Folder 13)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Storage Containers (Box 80, Folder 14)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Stove (Chulha) (Box 80, Folder 15)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Stove- Special (Box 80, Folder 16)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: String Cots (Charpoys) (Box 80, Folder 17)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Sugar Cane Crusher- Stone (Box 80, Folder 18)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Utensils for Making Curds (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Water Pipe (Hookah) (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Water Vessels (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Wheel Barrow (Box 80, Folder 22)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Winnowing Baskets and Sieves (Box 80, Folder 23)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Negatives of Indian Baskets (Box 80, Folder 23a)
      - Material Culture, Miscellaneous: Wooden Bed (Box 80, Folder 24)
      - Musical Instruments, Miscellaneous: Harmonium (Box 80, Folder 25)
      - Musical Instruments, Miscellanous: A Nona (Chamar), Musician (Box 80, Folder 26)
      - Musical Instruments, Miscellaneous: Singing Birhas (Box 80, Folder 27)
      - Outside Relations, Miscellaneous: Interants- Magician (Box 80, Folder 28)
      - Outside Relations, Miscellaneous: Interants- Mallah (Box 80, Folder 29)
      - Outside Relations, Miscellaneous: Interants- Muslim Pot Mender (Box 80, Folder 30)
      - Outside Relations, Miscellaneous: Outside Employment (Box 80, Folder 31)
      - Outside Relations, Miscellaneous: Transportation- Bus (Box 80, Folder 32)
      - Outside Relations, Places other than Senapur: Agra (Box 80, Folder 33)
      - Outside Relations, Places other than Senapur: Allahabad (Box 80, Folder 34)
      - Outside Relations, Places other than Senapur: Banaras (Box 80, Folder 35)
      - Outside Relations, Places other than Senapur: Calcutta (Box 80, Folder 36)
      - Outside Relations, Places other than Senapur: Jaunpur (Box 80, Folder 37)
      - Outside Relations, Places other than Senapur: Kerakat and Karakat Bazaar (Box 80, Folder 38)
      - Outside Relations, Places other than Senapur: Lucknow (Box 80, Folder 39)
      - Outside Relations, Places other than Senapur: New Delhi (Box 80, Folder 40)
      - Outside Relations, Places other than Senapur: Sarnath (Box 80, Folder 41)
      - Outside Relations, Places other than Senapur: Agra (Box 80, Folder 42)
      - Pictures (of People), Miscellaneous: People (Box 80, Folder 43)
      - Pictures (of People), People by Caste (alpha. by first name): Ahir (Box 80, Folder 44)
      - Pictures (of People), People by Caste (alpha. by first name): Bari (Box 80, Folder 45)
      - Pictures (of People), People by Caste (alpha. by first name): Bhar (Box 80, Folder 46)
      - Pictures (of People), People by Caste (alpha. by first name): Brahman (Box 80, Folder 47)
      - Pictures (of People), People by Caste (alpha. by first name): Chamar (Box 80, Folder 48)
      - Pictures (of People), People by Caste (alpha. by first name): Dafali (Box 80, Folder 49)
      - Pictures (of People), People by Caste (alpha. by first name): Dhobi (Box 80, Folder 50)
      - Pictures (of People), People by Caste (alpha. by first name): Kahar (Box 80, Folder 51)
      - Pictures (of People), People by Caste (alpha. by first name): Kohar (Box 80, Folder 52)
      - Pictures (of People), People by Caste (alpha. by first name): Lohar (Box 80, Folder 53)